ZHIYANG WANG

CONTACT

Room 454c, 3401 Walnut St,

Department of Electrical and Systems Engineering

University of Pennsylvania,

Philadelphia, PA, 19104, USA

Mobile: (+1)2676703385

E-mail: zhiyangw@seas.upenn.edu

Homepage: http://zhiyangw.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research is focused on the areas of wireless communications and machine learning. I am especially interested in large-scale graph neural networks and their theoretical analyses. Some of my projects include implementing machine learning techniques to solve problems in wireless communications. I am also focused on theoretical analyses of the limits of graph neural networks as manifold neural networks and their applications on point clouds.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania

2019-Present

Ph.D. candidate in Electrical Engineering

The Dean's Fellowship recipient

The Bruce Ford Memorial Fellowship recipent

Pennsylvania State University

Advisor: Prof. Jing Yang

Advisor: Prof. Alejandro Ribeiro

Visiting Scholar in Electrical Engineering

1 ioi. Jing Tang

2012-2019

Jul. 2018 - Dec. 2018

University of Science and Technology of China

Advisor: Prof. Cong Shen

Master in Electrical Engineering Bachelor in Electrical Engineering

Advisor: Prof. Cong Shen

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

University of Pennsylvania

Teaching Assistant

ESE 680-003, Graph Neural Networks

Fall 2020

ESE 224, Signal and Information Processing

Spring 2021

University of Science and Technology of China

Teaching Assistant

C programming

Spring 2015

MIMO wireless communications course

Fall 2017

PULICATIONS

Journal:

- **Z.** Wang, L. Ruiz and A. Ribeiro, "Stability to Deformations of Manifold Filters and Manifold Neural Networks", submitted.
- A. Parada-Mayorga, **Z. Wang**, F. Gama and A. Ribeiro, "Stability of Aggregation Graph Neural Networks", submitted to IEEE Transactions on Signal and Information Processing over Networks.
- **Z. Wang**, M. Eisen and A. Ribeiro, "Learning Decentralized Wireless Resource Allocations with Graph Neural Networks", IEEE Transactions on Signal Processing 70 (2022): 1850-1863.
- **Z. Wang**, R. Zhou, and C. Shen, "Regional Multi-Armed Bandits with Partial Informativeness", IEEE Trans. Signal Process., Volume: 66, Issue: 21, Page(s): 5705-5717, Nov. 2018

Z. Wang and C. Shen, "Small Cell Transmit Power Assignment Based on Correlated Bandit Learning", IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Communications, Vol. 35, No. 5, Page(s): 1030-1045, May 2017.

Conference:

- **Z. Wang**, L. Ruiz and A. Ribeiro, "Convolutional Neural Networks on Manifolds: From Graphs and Back", Accepted at 2022 Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers.
- **Z. Wang**, L. Ruiz and A. Ribeiro, "Stability of Neural Networks on Manifolds to Relative Perturbations", In ICASSP 2022-2022 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) (pp. 5473-5477). IEEE.
- **Z.** Wang, L. Ruiz, M. Eisen and A. Ribeiro, "Stable and Transferable Wireless Resource Allocation Policies via Manifold Neural Networks", In ICASSP 2022-2022 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) (pp. 8912-8916). IEEE.
- **Z.** Wang, L. Ruiz and A. Ribeiro, "Stability of Neural Networks on Riemannian Manifolds", , In 2021 29th European Signal Processing Conference (EUSIPCO) (pp. 1845-1849). IEEE. **Best Student Paper Award**
- **Z. Wang**, M. Eisen and A. Ribeiro, "Unsupervised Learning for Asynchronous Resource Allocation in Ad-hoc Wireless Networks", In ICASSP 2021-2021 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), pp. 8143-8147. IEEE, 2021.
- L. Ruiz, **Z. Wang** and A. Ribeiro, "Graph and Graphon Neural Network Stability", In ICASSP 2021-2021 IEEE International Conference on Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP), IEEE, 2021.
- **Z. Wang**, M. Eisen and A. Ribeiro, "Decentralized Wireless Resource Allocation with Graph Neural Networks", In 2020 54th Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers, pp. 299-303. IEEE, 2020.
- C. Shen, **Z. Wang**, S. S Villar and M. van der Schaar, "Learning for Dose Allocation in Adaptive Clinical Trials with Safety Constraints", In International Conference on Machine Learning, pp. 8730-8740. PMLR, 2020.
- **Z. Wang**, Z. Ying, and C. Shen, "Opportunistic Spectrum Access via Good Arm Identification", IEEE GlobalSIP 2018, Anaheim, California, USA, Nov. 2018.
- **Z. Wang** and C. Shen, "Small Cell Power Assignment with Unimodal Continuum-armed Bandits", 2018 IEEE International Conference on Communications Workshops on 5G-UDN.
- **Z. Wang**, R. Zhou, and C. Shen, "Regional Multi-Armed Bandits", Proceedings of the Twenty-First International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), PMLR 84:510-518, Playa Blanca, Lanzarote, Canary Islands, April 9-11, 2018.
- **Z. Wang**, C. Shen, X. Luo, M. van der Schaar, "Learn to Adapt: Self-Optimizing Small Cell Transmit Power with Correlated Bandit Learning", IEEE International Conference on Communications (ICC), 2017.

SKILLS

Programming: Pytorch, C, JAVA, MATLAB, Origin

Documentation: MS Office, LaTex

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

EUSIPCO Best Student Paper Award

Sep. 2021

Awarded by EURASIP to 3 student finalists at the paper competition Q&A

The Bruce Ford Memorial Fellowship

2019

Excellence fellowship granted by the University of Pennsylvania in addition to The Dean's Fellowship

| Granted by China's Ministry of Education to graduate students with excellent academic performance. | |
|--|-----------|
| IEEE ICC student Travel Grant | 2017 |
| Awarded by IEEE to cover for travel expenses. | |
| The First Prize in Graduate Academic Scholarship: USTC | 2016-2019 |
| Excellent Award: The Undergraduate Research Program in USTC | Oct.2015 |
| First prize of Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, Anhui | |
| Division | Sep. 2015 |
| Outstanding Student Scholarship: USTC | 2013-2015 |
| Outstanding Volunteer of the Chinese Young Volunteers Association | 2013 |